over time it is highly likely that you
will generate quite a lot of fails and
fall us on your computer the most modern
computers this isn't an issue as you
have high capacity disk drives cloud
storage or high capacity removable media
where files can be stored though there
may still be instances where you wish to
compress files this could be for
archiving into a limited space or it may
be that you need to send some files as
an attachment to an email and
compressing them will reduce the size of
the file that needs to be sent so to
compress a folder I'm going to
demonstrate with the itq folder so I'll
highlight the itq folder and simply
select a clock icon and select compress
itq this then is creating a zip file
as you can see indicated with the
follower the zip in the center of the
icon so once that's done might just
quickly move up there and that is then
compress that folder so just to see how
much it has compressed it by I can
highlight the itq folder and select get
info which will then give me the
information so that is one point eight
megabytes in size so the original size
was that and again I can highlight their
zip file and select get info and that
will lend give me the information on
that which is 1.5 megabyte which may not
seem much but if you bear in mind that
you could have quite a lot of fails and
a lot of flaws within there it can't
save quite a bit of space